welcome back folks welcome to another
episode of the soul talk podcast today's
episodes are going to be I think another
special one I'm actually very curious
and excited to interview my guest today
at the opportunity to him speak at a
very special conference an association
of transformational leaders last year
and I think he really shook the audience
those who were in attendance and brought
some profound perspective and insights
that were really really proud deep and
challenging in terms of a typical way we
we view life and see things and so I
think today's will be very interesting
so get the milk pads ready either
co-founder epi neuro hacker collective
director of research and development
which focused on developing processes
technologies for advancing medicine
human optimization here's a blog on
redesigning civilization at civilization
emerging I mean when I heard him speak I
consider him a philosopher so welcome to
the conversation today my friend Daniel
schmuck limburger Daniel welcome
thank to my friend I'm happy to be here
I'm looking forward to this conversation
great to have you on and so look I'm
curious I have a bunch of questions for
you but I'm curious especially for those
that may you know not know your work or
your blog or you know what you've been
sharing in terms of interviews can I saw
you speak and it was very very deep you
shared a lot of I think at least for me
profound insights what what exactly it's
my sound simple or strange but what
Daniel what exactly do you do I mean it
like are you a hack
I hear philosophy I mean for me you are
philosophizing you know are you what
what would you call yourself you know
what what do you do what you call
yourself what you know what I'm saying
well what's the deal
yeah
I don't know that really be all that
interested in calling myself anything
what do i what do I do I can talk about
what I'm interested in and things that
I'm that I put energy towards and study
and you mentioned a little bit
with regard to medicine and
biotechnology I
it's a area that I'm fascinated by and
love and so there's some attention in
that space that was actually kind of
unintentional that was because while I
was working on other things I had some
illness arise that was uncurable from
traditional methods and so I had to put
attention to seeing if I could figure
out some way to work with it and it
happened to be that some of the
scientific background and approach that
I have and working on things like
ecology and economies and like complex
systems were applicable to having new
insights and medicine so there's still
some work there my primary focus is
how do we design a civilization that
doesn't cause all of the problems that
the types of civilization that we
currently have in the past historically
environmental and social justice and war
and etc like what are the underlying
basis of all those problems
and can we actually change that at the
level of the design of a civilization
system itself so that looks like you
know whether we're looking at species
extinction or biodiversity loss of trees
getting cut down we we can see that
underneath all those issues you have the
fact that most trees are worth more cut
down than they are alive most animals
are worth more killed than they are
alive there's a perverse incentive
underneath that war is more profitable
than peace sick people are more
profitable than healthy people and so
you start to say okay well as long as a
problem is being incentivized it's not
going to stop and so that's like an
example of if we if we really want to
change the dynamics of the world we have
to change how people coordinate and how
they make sense of the world and what
they're incentivized to do in a deeper
way and kind of how I got into thinking
about this was I was as a kid I was
working in activism in a bunch of
different fields environmental stuff and
animal rights and social justice and we
made profoundly little progress and okay
I really want to understand why we're
humans like those of us in activism
it seems so clear that we don't want to
kill the elephants for their ivory or
clear cut the Amazon and yet so many
people and large corporations were
continuing to do those things so it's
like what is it that is driving all of
those how are they interconnected and
are there some foundational structures
that need addressed and I was you know
studying and a Systems Theory in
complexity and how how things fit
together at the same time and so that
just led to deeper and deeper inquiry
into
fundamental civilization design stuff so
you say kind of what do I do now with it
partly looks like looking at near-term
risks for the world and seeing how we
can mitigate those and then also looking
at how can we actually design new
systems of how humanity can make sense
of the world and make choices which is
like new methods of governance and
resource allocation that are
structurally different than the types of
top-down government's the types of
market systems we've had so far that
predispose different patterns of human
behavior that don't predispose for
environmental destruction and things
like that